Hector Obanana

Junior Software Developer

Peterborough

07306 891589 | hectorjana.o@gmail.com

github.com/hjaox | hectorobanana.netlify.app | linkedin.com/in/hector-obanana/

Personal Profile

I am making an exciting career change into Software Development making use of my problem-solving and analytical/logical thinking skills I have developed in my former career in the Electrical Engineering field. Took a 13-Week Boot Camp in Software engineering under a multi-award-winning tech education Northcoders to advance my knowledge in coding so I may gain the tools to build projects with increasing complexity, and as well experience working in a team environment to help me kick-start my career in the Software Development Industry.

Technical Skills

Languages: JavaScript

Front-End: HTML, CSS, React, React-Native (Expo), Axios, Tailwind CSS

Back-End: PostgreSQL, node-Postgres, Express, Node.js Testing: Test-Diven Development (TDD), Jest, Supertest

Hosting: Render, Netlify, ElephantSQL

Other: Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), Test-Driven Development (TDD), AGILE, SCRUM, KANBAN, Git

Projects

Personal Portfolio v1.1

A personal portfolio to house all my projects. I made my portfolio with React, JavaScript and Tailwind CSS.

Link to App: https://hectorobanana.netlify.app/ Technologies used: React, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript

Swim Wild

A social platform for a trend of wild swimming. The app provides a blend of user-generated and web scrapped content to inform users about nearby swimming spots that features safety consideration. Users can share their swimming experience with others, use statistics about their swimming history and learn more about their favorite spots via our API network and analysis of user content.

Technologies used: React Native, MongoDB, Google Maps API, Firebase, Jest, Node.js, Redux

Personal Portfolio v1

Earlier version of my portfolio. Made with vanilla HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Link to App: https://hjaox.qithub.io/ Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

NC News Front-end Project

The purpose of this repository is to serve as a front-end architecture for the back-end API that I have built (See NC News Back-end Project).

Link to App: https://nc-news-hjaox.netlify.app/ Technologies used: React, JavaScript, CSS, Axios

NC News Back-end Project

The purpose of this repository is to learn how to build an API for accessing application data programmatically. The intention is to mimic the building of a real-world backend services which should provide information to the front-end architecture.

Technologies used: JavaScript, PostgreSQL, Express, Jest, Supertest, node-Postgres

Experience

Junior Full Stack Software Developer, Northcoders - Software Engineering Bootcamp (Jul 2023 - Ongoing)

During the 13-week Bootcamp where I learned the fundamentals of Full-Stack Development, I acquired the fundamentals of JavaScript which helped me in creating a back-end service to provide data for a front-end architecture that I have built. All throughout the process, I aimed to build clean testable codes by following Test Driven Development process with agile methodologies while both working solo or working with colleagues through pair-programming or in group projects.

Plant Operator, SUEZ Water Technologies and Solutions UK L P (Feb 2022 – Sept 2022)

- Quality Control of different types of water treatment equipment
- Troubleshooting electrical and control systems in fleet equipment

Admin Staff, Clippers Logistics (PE3) under Staffing Match Agency (Aug 2021 – Feb 2022)

Cooperating with several departments to allocate orders for E-commerce and Retail Customers

Technician, Bake n'Cake in Dubai (Nov 2019 – Mar 2020)

Maintaining equipment operation and other electrical systems in of the building

Building Engineer, First Oceanic Property Management Inc. In Philippines (March 2017 - May 2018)

- Managing the operation of the building (Three Techno Place Building) both staff (Security, Housekeeping and Maintenance Crew) and equipment system (Mechanical, Electrical, etc.)
- Performing basic in-house Preventive Maintenance daily and monthly of building systems

Site Engineer, Golden Sky Trading and Engineering Services WLL in Qatar (July 2015 – March 2016)

- Design and help fabricate Motor Control Panels/Protection (MCP)
- Supervision of Manpower on other tasks

Education

Central Philippine University: Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

UK Comparison Framework Levels: RFQ Level 5 / SCQF Level 8 / CQFW Level 5

Comparable UK Qualifications: Foundation Degree / BTEC Level 5 / SQA Higher / National Diploma (HND) (SCQF Level 8)